STEVE ROLLINS **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

coding61.sr@gmail.com

**** 206-940-5274

North Bend, WA

in steven-rollins

greenhornsr

over 10 years of prior experience as a mobility sales representative. JAVASCRIPT, PYTHON, REACT, exposure in ANGULAR, MongoDB, about developing quality quality of life & building highquality experiences for end-users. Eager to continue to grow as a contributor with an equally strong people, and development work.

INTERESTS INCLUDE:

Molding Digital Clay(Coding)!

Combat Sports

Basketball

Football

VOLUNTEERING:

Mt. Si View (SVSD) Head Coach Basketball Taught 12+ 6th graders basic and parent volunteers, managed game facilitated team community and

i-9 Sports Flag Football Assistant Coach Introduced and taught 15+ 1st graders Flag Football; organized

Soccer Assistant Coach Introduced and taught 8+ kindergarteners how to play

Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, NodeJS, React, Redux, SQL-Lite, REST, GraphQL, Python, PostgreSQL, Less/Sass, Flask, Django, Angular, Jest, SQL

Projects

Apr. 2020 to Current ghsr-portfolio

BUILT WITH: HTML | CSS | JS | REACT Independent one-stop-shop showcase project.

- Folder/file structure is built with simplicity and reusability in mind.
- · Developed a ticker, expandable/interactive summary section, live social media links, downloadable Resume, and a streamlined email method.

URL to portfolio site: https://steven-d-rollins-portfolio.netlify.app/

YELP-FEELERS Oct. 2019

BUILT WITH: HTML | CSS | JS | REACT | REDUX | NODE.JS | EXPRESS | KNEX | POSTGRESQL | PYTHON | JWT I YELP API

A remote cross-functional team project tasked with building an application that leveraged the YELP API to produce modified review results based on user sentiment analysis.

- · Built application with a fully remote team of 8 Full Stack Web Development and Data Science students.
- 4 days expected time for completion.
- Individual responsibilities included Leading the project team as well as producing the BackEnd of the project.
- Utilized Node JS and Express to set up the server environment and API; used KNEX to translate JS to SQL and deploy the PostgreSQL Database; also used the API and JWT to validate client-side user data sent to the Backend.

URL to deployed site: https://practical-lamport-cc4fcf.netlify.app/

Chicago Array of Things June 2019

BUILT WITH: HTML | CSS | JS | REACT | REDUX | NODE.JS | EXPRESS | KNEX | POSTGRESQL | PYTHON | AOT

Chicago Array of Things; an ambitious project to allow users to view preferred data collected by the Chicago AOT sensors.

- Built application with a fully remote team of 8 Full Stack Web Development and Data Science students within a deadline of 4 days.
- Solely responsible for working with the Back End to produce a Front End that included a client-side authorization, login, registration, and producing a query interface for the user that would present a graph returned from the Back End / DS team linked to the chosen query.

URL to deployed site: https://chicago-aot.netlify.app/

Employment

Lambda School

Remote

Team Lead

Aug. 2019 to Nov. 2019

- Supported the learning and professional growth of 10-15 Full Stack Web development students.
- Mentored students in the understanding of HTML, CSS, JS, React, Hooks, Redux, Context, Express, NodeJS, SQLite3, PSQL, and other associated concepts such as data types, accessibility, automated testing, etc.

Verizon Bellevue, WA

Major Accounts Manager - Healthcare

lune 2013 to May 2015

- · Identified and introduced HIPAA compliant partner solutions that solved the mobility needs of western Washington's largest healthcare systems, consisting of more than 500 plus employees.
- Ensured proposed solutions met minimal compliance security protocols, industry regulations, budgets, and satisfied objectives with patient safety front of mind.
- Successfully inked first in market Verizon Remote Patient Care solution.
- Successfully sold and deployed a major primary/redundant communication solution utilized by more than 2,500 users.

Verizon Wireless

Denver, CO

Business Account Executive

Nov. 2007 to June 2013

- · Procurement, expansion, and long term management of prospective and existing customer base for businesses that had employee counts mostly ranging from 5-499.
- Routinely met and exceeded monthly sales quota; achieved 100% or better.

Education

Lambda School - Remote Full Stack Web Development Computer Science

Apr. 2019 to Current

Coding Dojo - Seattle, WA Full Stack Web Development

Oct. 2016 to Jan. 2017